[upbeat music]
[car horn honks] - Mom! Your cab's here.
妈妈！你的出租车来了。
- I can drive myself.
我可以自己开车。
- No. Your relaxation starts now.
不行。你的放松现在就开始。
- We love you.
我们爱你。
- And we want you to have fun on your spaghetti-way.
我们希望你在你的‘意大利面之旅’上玩得开心。
- Dicky, it's a "spa getaway."
Dicky，这是一个‘水疗度假’。
- You know, where you get massages,
你知道，就是去做按摩，
and pedicures, and facials?
修脚和面部护理的地方？
- I know. I pronounce things weird summertimes.
我知道。我有时候发音怪怪的。
- Just go. [car horn honks]
- 去吧。
- You know, I don't know. Maybe this isn't the best weekend.
- 你知道，我不确定。也许这个周末不是最好的选择。
- No, no, no. this is the only weekend.
- 不，不，不。这是唯一的机会。
I bought this gift certificate a year ago. It expires Monday. You have to go.
我一年前买了这张礼品券。它周一就过期了。你必须去。
- I guess.
- 我想也是。
I just don't like leaving the kids all alone.
我只是不喜欢把孩子单独留下来。
- You mean with me? - Right.
- 你是说和我一起？ - 对。
- No, of course I meant with you. - Yeah.
- 不，当然我是说和你一起。 - 是的。
- Don't worry, Mom.
- 别担心，妈妈。
- It's gonna be fine. - That's what you all said the last time I went away for the weekend, and I came home to
- 一切都会好的。 - 上次我周末离开时你们也是这么说的，结果我回家发现
you kids carving ice sculptures in the living room.
你们这些孩子在客厅里雕刻冰雕。
- Dad said we had to be creative.
- 爸爸说我们必须有创意。
- You were using a chainsaw.
- 你们用的是电锯。
- Creatively. - Okay.
- 有创意地。 - 好吧。
- And there was no rule against it.
- 而且当时没有规则禁止这样做。
- Which is why now there is a rule against it.
- 这就是为什么现在有了禁止这样做的规则。
Along with a whole bunch of other rules
还有一大堆其他的规则
that are in my Big Book of Rules to keep the kids in line.
都在我的《规则大全》里，用来管住孩子们。
- Okay, so when you say a big book do you mean actually a--
- 好吧，你说的大全是指实际上的——
Oh, Mama, that's a big book.
哦，妈妈，那真的是一本大书。
- For example rule #6.
例如规则#6。
No making ice sculptures in the living room.
禁止在客厅制作冰雕。
- What about sculptures made out of--
那用其他材料做的雕塑呢——
- Or butter, or cheese, or food of any kind.
或者黄油、奶酪，任何种类的食物都不行。
[all groan]
（大家一起叹气）
See, hon? They're groaning.
看，亲爱的？他们在叹气。
I got this.
我明白了。
It'll be good for you.
这对你们有好处。
- You need to go and relax.
你需要去放松一下。
- I do. I really do.
我确实需要。真的需要。
- Face it. We stress you out.
面对现实吧，我们让你感到压力。
- You do. You really do.
确实如此，真的让你感到压力。
- You know who else stresses you out? Dad.
你知道还有谁让你感到压力吗？爸爸。
- I do. - You really do.
是的。
[car horn honks] Hold your horses!
别急！
I am coming!
我来了！
Wow. I really need this.
哇，我真的需要这个。
all: You do. You really do.
你确实需要。
- Okay. I will see you guys in a couple of days.
好吧，过几天见。
I love you so much. - Bye.
我非常爱你。再见。
- I love you, Mom. - Please be good. - Mom, we'll miss you. - I miss you already.
- 我爱你，妈妈。 - 请保重。 - 妈妈，我们会想你的。 - 我已经想你了。
- Love you.
- 爱你。
- All right. Mom is gone.
- 好了，妈妈走了。
Hey, Dad, nice one on the fake rulebook.
嘿，爸爸，伪造的规则书做得不错。
She totally bought it. All right.
她完全相信了。好吧。
You all have your assignments:
你们都有各自的任务：
whipped cream, chips, donkey.
奶油、薯片、驴。
I'll get the saddle and spoons.
我去拿马鞍和勺子。
- Wait! This is not a fake rulebook.
- 等等！这不是假的规则书。
This is serious.
这是认真的。
- So no donkey?
- 所以没有驴子？
[all deflated] Eee-aww.
[全都泄气了] 咦-啊。
- Listen, guys, your mom should be able to go away and relax without having to worry about us
- 听着，伙计们，你们的妈妈应该能够离开并放松，而不必担心我们
which is why I made the Big Book of Rules.
这就是为什么我制定了规则大全。
- [groans] These rules are ridiculous.
- [叹气] 这些规则太荒谬了。
- You guys are just going to have to deal with it. - But-- - Ah.
- 你们就只能接受它了。 - 但是-- - 啊。
When you pay the rent you can make the rules.
当你付房租的时候，你就可以制定规则。
- [groans]
- [叹气]
- I can't believe this.
- 我简直不敢相信。
He's treating us like little kids.
他像对待小孩子一样对待我们。
- Yeah. We're old enough.
是的，我们都这么大了。
We should be able to make our own rules.
我们应该能够制定自己的规则。
- Yeah. - Yeah, and how could we ever
是的。
pay the rent with the tiny allowance he gives us?
是的，他给我们的那点零花钱怎么可能付得起房租？
He's rigged the whole system.
他操纵了整个系统。
all: Yeah.
没错。
- Wait a minute.
等等。
We're going to rig it back.
我们要反过来操纵它。
We just need to figure out a way
我们只需要想出一个办法
to make enough money so we can pay the rent.
赚足够的钱来支付房租。
Then we can make the rules.
那我们就可以制定规则了。
- We should probably cancel that donkey.
- 我们或许应该取消那个驴子。
[hoofs clop]
[蹄声]
- Too late. - Shh.
- 太晚了。 - 嘘。
- Don't answer the door.
- 别开门。
- We're not home!
- 我们不在家！
[donkey brays, hoofs clop]
[驴叫，蹄声]
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
- ♪ Na na na na na na na na na na na ♪ - ♪ Hey! ♪
- ♪ 呐呐呐呐呐呐呐呐呐呐 ♪ - ♪ 嘿！ ♪
- ♪ Na na na na na na na na na na na ♪
- ♪ 呐呐呐呐呐呐呐呐呐呐 ♪
[whistling]
[吹口哨]
♪ ♪
- ♪ One, two, three, four! ♪
- ♪ 一，二，三，四！ ♪
♪ ♪
- ♪ Na na na na na na ♪
- ♪ 呐呐呐呐呐呐 ♪
♪ Na na na na na na ♪ - ♪ Hey! ♪
♪ 呐呐呐呐呐呐 ♪ - ♪ 嘿！ ♪
♪ One, two ♪ - ♪ Na na na na na na ♪
♪ 一，二 ♪ - ♪ 呐呐呐呐呐呐 ♪
- ♪ One, two, three, four! ♪
- ♪ 一，二，三，四！ ♪
- ♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh-oh ♪
- ♪ 哦，哦，哦，哦-哦 ♪
- Come on, guys. Think!
- 来吧，伙计们。想想！
There's got to be a way we can make money.
肯定有办法我们可以赚钱。
- Perhaps some of my refreshing lemonade
- 也许我那提神的柠檬水
will help stimulate our thinking muscles.
能帮助激发我们的思考肌肉。
all: Mmm.
大家：嗯。
- This is good stuff.
- 这东西不错。
- You could totally sell this.
- 你完全可以卖这个。
- Yeah. You'd make a fortune.
- 是的。你会发大财的。
[cell phone chimes] - Who's that?
[手机铃声] - 谁啊？
- Oh, it's just Oscar.
- 哦，是奥斯卡。
He's got a hankering for some lemonade
他突然想喝点柠檬水
and is wondering where he can buy some.
并且想知道在哪里可以买到。
- Well, text him back, and tell him we're too busy
- 好吧，给他回个短信，告诉他我们太忙了
worrying about our money problems
担心我们的财务问题
to worry about his lemonade-buying problems.
没空担心他的买柠檬水问题。
- Yeah.
- 是啊。
- No, wait.
- 不，等等。
We can solve both problems!
我们可以解决这两个问题！
We should open up a lemonade stand.
我们应该开一个柠檬水摊。
- [gasps] Of course. I'll get the lemons.
- [吸气] 当然。我去拿柠檬。
- I'll work the cash register.
- 我来负责收银台。
- I'll go to the bathroom.
- 我要去洗手间。
- How is that gonna help? - It's not.
- 那有什么用？ - 没用。
I just had a lot of lemonade.
我只是喝了很多柠檬水。
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
♪ ♪
[soothing music]
[舒缓的音乐]
- Namaste. - Oh, great.
- 纳玛斯提。 - 哦，太好了。
You're here.
你来了。
Apparently I really need to relax,
显然我真的很需要放松，
so let's get this rub show on the road.
所以让我们开始这个按摩之旅吧。
- Just take a deep breath, clear your mind,
- 只需深呼吸，清空思绪，
and leave the outside world outside.
并将外界的一切抛诸脑后。
- Okay.
- 好的。
Letting go.
放下一切。
♪ ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ 哦 ♪
Ooh, I feel like I'm swimming in a sea of tranquility.
哦，我感觉自己仿佛在宁静之海中遨游。
[both giggle]
[两人轻笑]
[cell phone rings]
[手机铃声响起]
- I'm so sorry. That's my phone.
- 非常抱歉。是我的手机。
I thought I had turned that off.
我以为我已经关掉了。
I'll just be one second.
我马上就好。
Hey, sweetie.
嘿，亲爱的。
I'm in a session, but what's up?
我在开会，怎么了？
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
I'm sure it'll be okay.
我相信会没事的。
Well, then put him on.
那让他接电话。
Jeremy, put your pants on!
杰里米，把裤子穿上！
Give your father his keys back,
把钥匙还给你爸爸，
and take your retainer out of the baby's mouth!
把你的保持器从宝宝嘴里拿出来！
Kids, huh? - Oh!
孩子啊？ - 哦！
Okay. [groans]
好吧。[呻吟]
Too much pressure! Too much pressure!
压力太大了！压力太大了！
- Tell me about it.
- 说得太对了。
Every time I leave that house
每次我离开那个家
I'm afraid of what I'm going to come home to.
我都害怕回家会看到什么。
- What?
- 什么？
[whines] Mama.
[抱怨] 妈妈。
[upbeat music]
[欢快音乐]
♪ ♪
- I have a large for Natalie.
- 我有一个大杯给娜塔莉。
Nat-a-lie?
娜-塔-莉？
- It's "Natlee!" The "a" is silent!
- 是“娜特莉”！“a”不发音！
- Sorry.
- 对不起。
- You call this a large?
- 你管这个叫大杯？
- Sorry. - Sorry. - Sorry?
- 对不起。 - 对不起。 - 对不起？
- You know, maybe I should start calling out the names.
- 你知道，也许我应该开始大声念出名字。
- Don't worry. I got this.
- 别担心。我搞得定。
I have a medium for Twrmnym.
我有一个中杯给特维米姆。
- "Twrmnym" is not a name.
- “Twrmnym”不是个名字。
It's just smeared. Here.
这只是涂污了。这里。
Um, Timothy?
嗯，Timothy？
Theodore?
Theodore？
- Twrmnym?
- Twrmnym？
- You call this a medium?
- 你管这个叫中杯？
- You guys are using the wrong cups!
- 你们用错杯子了！
- So how much longer until we can pay the rent
- 那我们还要多久才能付得起房租
and start making our own rules?
然后开始制定自己的规则？
- At this rate, if we stay open 'til dinner...
- 照这样下去，如果我们营业到晚餐时间...
nine years. - [groans]
九年。 - [呻吟]
Oh, wait, I forgot to carry the 2.
哦，等等，我忘了进2。
29 years.
29年。
- Hello, friends.
- 你好，朋友们。
I think that I'll have a large lemonade to wet my whistle,
我想我会来一大杯柠檬水润润喉咙，
and do you guys have anything to nibble on?
你们这里有啥可以嚼嚼的吗？
- Sorry. We don't sell nibbles here.
- 抱歉。我们这里不卖零食。
- To just anyone, but for you one nibble coming right up.
- 对别人不行，但对你，马上就来一份小零食。
- Thanks, doll.
- 谢谢，宝贝。
- What are you doing?
- 你在干什么？
- If we start selling food we'll make more money.
如果我们开始卖食物，我们会赚更多钱。
- Yeah, but where are you going to get a nibble?
是啊，但你打算从哪儿弄点小吃？
- You leave the nibbles to me.
小吃的事交给我。
[upbeat music]
[欢快音乐]
- Sorry, Squish.
对不起，Squish。
This is my reward for being Super Dad.
这是我作为超级爸爸的奖励。
Living room's clean, kids are safe,
客厅干净，孩子们安全，
and the laundry's almost done.
而且衣服也快洗好了。
[bell rings]
[铃声响起]
It's the Dad-Signal.
是爸爸信号。
There's trouble in Clotham City.
Clotham City有麻烦了。
To the laundry room!
去洗衣房！
Hey, don't even think about stealing my sandwich, Squishy.
嘿，Squishy，别想偷我的三明治。
[mutters]
[咕哝]
I got eyes in the back of my head.
我后脑勺有眼睛。
- [Squishy whines]
- [Squishy哀叫]
- Nothing gets by me.
- 没有什么能逃过我的眼睛。
[whistles]
[吹口哨]
[humming]
[哼唱]
[gasps]
[惊呼]
Squishy Paws Tiberius Harper!
斯奎西·帕斯·泰伯利厄斯·哈珀！
I was gonna make you my side pup.
我本打算让你成为我的副手小狗。
[upbeat music]
[欢快音乐]
- Hey, bros. Let me get a lemonade,
- 嘿，兄弟们。给我来杯柠檬水，
and what do you guys got to grub on?
还有你们这儿有什么吃的？
- We're all out of food,
- 我们的食物都卖完了，
but we're expecting a new shipment any minute.
但新货随时会到。
- Okay I found six-and-a-half fish sticks
- 好的，我找到了六根半的鱼条
and two day old meatloaf.
和两天前的肉糕。
- Leftovers?
- 剩菜吗？
Nobody's going to buy two day old meatloaf.
没人会买两天前的肉饼。
- They will if we call it "deliciously aged."
如果我们称之为“美味陈年”，他们就会买。
- Deliciously aged meatloaf?
美味陈年肉饼？
I'll take it.
我要了。
- It doesn't matter anyway.
反正也没关系。
We're working our fingers to the bone,
我们累得手指都快断了，
and we're still not making enough money to pay the rent.
还是赚不够钱付房租。
- I wish there was a way we could make money without actually having to work.
真希望有一种不用实际工作就能赚钱的方法。
[cell phone rings]
[手机铃声响起]
- Hey, Mom.
嘿，妈妈。
Just getting some lemonade.
只是在买柠檬水。
Don't worry.
别担心。
I'll get the van off the front lawn.
我会把面包车从前草坪上弄走的。
I don't know. I can't park it in the street.
我不知道。我不能把它停在街上。
I just got to find someone who will let me pay them
我只需要找到一个愿意让我付钱给他们的人
a lot of money to park in their garage.
让我停在他们的车库。
- A little bit more. Little bit more.
再稍微多一点。再稍微多一点。
Little bit more and stop.
再稍微多一点就停。
- This is awesome.
太棒了。
Thanks, dudes. My mom's gonna be stoked.
谢谢，伙计们。我妈会很高兴的。
- Of course before you can officially rent out our garage
当然，在你正式租用我们的车库停放你的货车之前，
for your van there is the little matter of a rental agreement.
还有一份租赁协议的小事要处理。
Just sign here, here, and here.
只需在这里、这里和这里签字。
- Shouldn't I read it first?
我不应该先读一下吗？
- If you want. - Yeah. I don't want.
如果你想的话。 - 是的，我不想。
- This makes me nervous.
这让我感到紧张。
Are we sure this isn't against the rules?
我们确定这不是违反规定吗？
- Absolutely. 19 pages of things we can't do in the garage.
绝对不是。19页的内容是我们不能在车库做的事情。
No mention of letting someone park a van.
没有提到让某人停放货车。
- Here you go, little lawyer man.
给你，小律师先生。
- Thank you, and now to complete our transaction--
- 谢谢，现在来完成我们的交易——
- Rock on. Whoo!
- 继续摇滚。哇！
- No, you need to pay us the rent.
- 不，你需要付给我们租金。
- Oh, right. Give me a minute.
- 哦，对。给我一分钟。
I just got to collect it from the guys first.
我得先从那些家伙那里收钱。
- Um, what guys?
- 呃，哪些家伙？
- This is Snakebite... - [hisses]
- 这是Snakebite... - [嘶嘶声]
- Skull Crusher... - [growls]
- Skull Crusher... - [咆哮声]
- And Tim.
- 还有Tim。
Don't look Tim in the eye.
别直视Tim的眼睛。
- Okay. Well, just as long as you pay us before you leave.
好吧，只要你离开前付清给我们就行。
- Leave? Oh, we're not leaving.
离开？哦，我们不走。
We're practicing living in the van.
我们正在练习住在面包车里。
Don't want any surprises when we go on tour.
我们去巡演时不想有任何意外。
- Tour? - Yeah. We're a band.
巡演？
We are Frogtown! all: Ribbit.
对，我们是个乐队。
- Uh-oh. Rule 17.
我们是‘蛙镇乐队’！
No renting out the garage to rock bands.
所有人：呱呱。
- Maybe Dad will be so caught up in making the house
哎呀。第17条规则。
perfect for Mom he won't even notice.
不准把车库租给摇滚乐队。
- Yeah.
是的。
[rock music] ♪ Ribbit! Ribbit! ♪
♪ 呱！呱！ ♪
- I think he's gonna notice! - ♪ Ribbit! Ribbit! ♪
我觉得他会注意到的！
♪ Ribbit! Ribbit! ♪
♪ 呱！呱！ ♪
[rock music] - ♪ Ribbit! Ribbit! ♪
♪ ♪
- We need to get them to stop!
我们需要让他们停下来！
- Why? They rock!
为什么？他们很棒！
- We need to kick them out! - We can't!
我们需要把他们赶出去！
We signed a rental agreement!
我们不能！我们签了租赁协议！
- That was written by an 11-year-old!
那是一个11岁小孩写的！
This can't hold up! - Oh, it can! I'm very good!
这可站不住脚！- 噢，它可以！我可是很厉害的！
Sorry, but they have all the power!
抱歉，但他们拥有所有权力！
- Well, what if we gave them a little less power!
好吧，如果我们让他们少一点权力呢！
♪ Ribbit! Ribbit! ♪
♪ 青蛙叫！青蛙叫！♪
♪ ♪
[yells] No power...
没有电力...
[sighs] No band practice.
叹气 没有乐队练习了。
- Hey, that's great, but what do we do about Dad?
- 嘿，这很棒，但我们怎么处理爸爸呢？
- Nothing. He obviously didn't hear it.
- 什么也不做。他显然没听到。
- Hey, kids, what was that noise?
嘿，孩子们，那是什么声音？
- Or we come up with an excuse. Quick. Ideas, go!
或者我们编个借口。快，想主意，快！
- Rock 'n roll ice cream truck. - No.
摇滚冰淇淋车。
- Army of angry cats? - Not believable.
不行。
- We rented out the garage to a really loud band.
愤怒的猫军队？
- Rock 'n roll ice cream truck it is. Go, go, go!
不可信。
- Hey, kids, did you hear that?
我们把车库租给了一个非常吵的乐队。
It sounded like there's an army of angry cats in the garage.
那就摇滚冰淇淋车吧。快，快，快！
- Well, it couldn't be that,
嘿，孩子们，你们听到了吗？
because that wouldn't be believable.
听起来像是车库里有一群愤怒的猫。
- I better go check. - Oh, you probably should.
- 我最好去看看。 - 哦，你大概应该去。
Of course that would make Mom right.
当然，那会让妈妈说对了。
- About what? - She said you'd never be
- 关于什么？ - 她说你永远无法
able to finish all the housework
完成所有的家务活
because you're always getting distracted by something.
因为你总是被某事分心。
- What? No, I don't. - Of course you don't.
- 什么？不，我没有。 - 当然你没有。
That's why you're going right back upstairs
这就是为什么你马上要回到楼上
to finish all the work.
去完成所有的工作。
- You're darn right I am,
- 你说得对，我会的，
and not even an army of angry cats can stop me!
甚至一群愤怒的猫也阻止不了我！
Wait, what was I doing?
等等，我刚才在做什么？
Oh, okay.
哦，好吧。
[all sigh]
[大家都叹气]
- Hey, little landlords... [all gasp]
- 嘿，小房东们... [大家都惊讶]
Power's out in the garage.
车库的电源断了。
- You know, that's probably a good thing.
- 你知道，这可能是个好事。
You guys have been rocking out for a while,
你们已经摇滚了一段时间了，
and you sound perfect.
而且你们听起来很完美。
You could use a break.
你们可以休息一下。
- You're right. We could use a break.
- 你说得对。我们可以休息一下。
Hey, Frogtown, take five.
嘿，Frogtown，休息五分钟。
So what's the waffle sitch in here?
那么这里的华夫饼情况如何？
- What?
什么？
- "Sitch" is how us cool guys say "situation,"
“Sitch”是我们这些酷哥说“情况”的方式，
and "waffle" is how we say "square bumpy pancake."
而“waffle”是我们说“方形凹凸煎饼”的方式。
- I know what he meant.
我知道他是什么意思。
- Excuse me, Mr. Snakebite?
对不起，Snakebite先生？
Frogtowners...
you guys can't really be in the house.
你们不能真的待在屋里。
- It doesn't say that in the rental agreement.
租赁协议里没这么写。
- [hisses] - I don't know. I'll ask.
- [嘶嘶声] - 我不知道。我去问问。
He wants to know what kind of syrup you guys roll with.
他想知道你们用的是哪种糖浆。
- Um, you can't roll with our syrup.
- 嗯，你们不能用我们的糖浆。
You need to roll back into the garage.
你们需要滚回车库里去。
- No, that's where we rock.
- 不，那里是我们摇滚的地方。
We're gonna roll into the living room.
我们要滚进客厅。
- No-- - [growls]
- 不-- - [咆哮声]
- He just rolled with my mangoes.
- 他刚刚滚走了我的芒果。
Excuse me, but those are my--
对不起，但那些是我的--
never mind.
算了。
- Listen, we may not have been specific
听着，我们可能没在租房协议里说得太清楚，
with the rental agreement,
但这房子还是有一本行为规范大册子的，
but there still is a Big Book of Rules for this house,
其中一条就是你们不能待在这里。
and one of them is you cannot be in here.
- 如果我们不喜欢这条规则呢？
- What if we don't like that rule?
- 对不起，只有交了房租的人才能制定规则。
- Sorry. When you pay the rent you can make the rules.
- 哦，对哦。我忘了。
- Oh, yeah. I forgot.
现在我们交了房租，
Now we do pay the rent,
我的第一条规则就是‘蛙城想干啥就干啥’。
and my first rule is Frogtown does whatever Frogtown wants.
- （嘶嘶声）- 我去问问看。
- [hisses] - I'll ask.
嘿，为什么你们家被列入了驴子‘不派送’名单？
Hey, why is your house on the donkey "no deliver" list?
嘿，为什么你家的房子在驴子“不配送”名单上？
- Well, if we can't get a donkey, well, we should at least rock in here.
嗯，如果我们不能用驴子，那至少我们该在这里摇滚。
- Yeah, let's get our gear. all: Ribbit!
对，我们去拿我们的装备。
- We have got to get them out of here!
我们必须把他们赶出去！
- But they paid the rent. They make the rules.
但他们付了房租。他们制定规则。
- No. We make the rules. Follow me.
不，我们制定规则。跟我来。
[upbeat music]
[欢快音乐]
- See if I can find that video
看看我能不能找到那个视频
that teaches you how to fold a shirt in two seconds.
教你如何在两秒钟内叠好一件衬衫。
Top ten funniest groin kicks? Yes, please.
十大最搞笑的腹股沟踢击？是的，请。
[barks]
[吠叫]
Oh, you're right.
哦，你说得对。
I will not get distracted.
我不会分心。
I am folding laundry.
我在叠衣服。
- Need to fold a shirt fast? - Sure do.
- 需要快速叠衬衫吗？ - 当然需要。
- Just follow these simple instructions.
- 只需遵循这些简单的指示。
- First, reach into one sleeve...
- 首先，伸进一个袖子...
- Done. - Then the other.
- 完成了。 - 然后是另一个。
- Done.
- 完成了。
- Pull backward, and switch.
- 向后拉，然后交换。
- What have I done?
- 我做了什么？
[grunts]
[咕哝]
Go get help, Squishy!
去求救，Squishy！
[cries]
[哭泣]
- Hey, Dad, got a sec?
- 嘿，爸爸，有空吗？
- Oh, hey, kids.
- 哦，嘿，孩子们。
Just doing some laundry.
正在洗衣服。
- Okay, so you know how you said we could make the rules
- 好的，你知道你说过如果我们付房租，
if we pay the rent? Well, here's the rent.
我们就可以制定规则吗？这是房租。
Now we get to make the rules. - First new rule.
现在我们可以制定规则了。- 第一条新规则。
We are allowed to rent out the garage to a rock band.
我们可以把车库租给一个摇滚乐队。
- Whoa, whoa, whoa. Slow down.
- 哇，哇，哇。慢点。
Did you rent out the garage to a rock band?
你把车库租给了一个摇滚乐队吗？
- Yep. - Totally.
- 是的。 - 完全正确。
- One of them just hisses. - [groans]
- 其中一个刚刚发出嘶嘶声。 - [呻吟]
"When you pay the rent you can make the rules"
“当你付了房租就可以制定规则”
is just a figure of speech.
只是一种修辞手法。
- Wai--It is? - Yeah.
- 等--是吗？ - 是的。
It's just a thing that parents say,
这只是父母说的话，
like, "You'll understand when you're older."
比如，“等你长大了就会明白。”
I'm older, I don't understand anything.
我年纪大了，什么都不懂。
Look at me. I'm caught in a shirt!
看看我，被一件衬衫困住了！
- What do we do about the band?
- 我们怎么处理乐队的事？
- Don't you worry.
- 别担心。
I'm the parent. I make the rules.
我是家长，我定规矩。
Just get some scissors and cut me out of this shirt.
拿把剪刀，把我从这件衬衫里剪出来。
- The book said no scissors.
- 书上说不能用剪刀。
- Just read the last page of the book.
- 把书最后一页读一下。
- "All rules are null and void in the event
- “如果父亲被衬衫困住，所有规则都无效。”
your father gets caught in a shirt."
- 你考虑得真周到。
You thought of everything.
你想得真周到。
- Go get the scissors!
- 去拿剪刀！
And run back!
然后跑回来！
[upbeat music]
[轻快的音乐]
♪ ♪
- Just let go,
- 放手吧，
and everything will be fine.
一切都会好起来的。
I said let go of your brother now.
我说了现在放开你弟弟。
Let go!
放手！
- Ow. - Let go!
- 哎哟。 - 放手！
- [screams] Maybe you should let go!
- [尖叫] 也许你应该放手！
- I'd love to let go, but not all of us
- 我很想放手，但不是我们所有人
can just walk out of the house for the weekend
都能在周末轻松地走出家门而不发生大灾难。
without a big disaster happening.
你的孩子们在烤棉花糖吗？
Are your kids roasting marshmallows?
- 哎呀。 - 在你的燃烧沙发上？
- Aw. - Over your burning couch?
- 啊！希望不是！
- Ahh! I hope not!
[呜咽]
[whimpers]
[欢快的音乐]
[upbeat music]
- 哦，是的！甜美的尖叫。
- Oh, yeah! Sweet screech.
- 我们应该把这个声音融入我们的下一首歌。
- We should work that sound into our next song.
- 我们应该把那个声音融入到我们的下一首歌里。
- Look at this scratch!
- 看看这个划痕！
- Hey, dudes, what's for dinner?
- 嘿，伙计们，晚餐吃什么？
- Whatever your parents are making,
- 随便你父母做什么，
'cause you're not staying here.
- 因为你不会留在这里。
- Who's this guy?
- 这家伙是谁？
- I'm the dad, and I'm in charge.
- 我是爸爸，我说了算。
- Well, we're Frogtown, and we signed a rental agreement.
- 我们是Frogtown，我们签了租赁协议。
- [hisses]
- [嘶嘶声]
- Snakebite says his dad's a lawyer.
- Snakebite说他爸爸是律师。
That thing's ironclad.
那东西是铁板钉钉的。
- I heard what he said.
- 我听到了他的话。
Should have never sent you to law camp,
真不该送你去法律营，
but you got me to sign that contract, and I couldn't get out of it.
但你让我签了那份合同，我无法摆脱。
Harper huddle.
哈珀，集合。
All right, we got to get this band out of here before your mother gets home,
好吧，我们得在这之前把乐队弄出去，
or she is gonna be very angry with you.
不然你妈妈回来会对你非常生气的。
- Uh, don't you mean she'll be very angry with you?
- 呃，你不是说你妈妈会对你非常生气吗？
- Of course that's what I mean!
- 当然，我就是这个意思！
[rock music] [all groan]
[摇滚音乐] [所有人呻吟]
♪ Ribbit! ♪
♪呱！♪
- I can't think with all this noise!
- 我无法在这噪音中思考！
- ♪ Ribbit! Ribbit! ♪ - That's it!
- ♪呱！呱！♪ - 够了！
You think they're noisy?
你觉得他们吵吗？
Wait 'til they get a load of us!
等着看他们对我们的反应吧！
- ♪ Ribbit! Ribbit! ♪
- ♪呱！呱！♪
- Sup, Frogtown.
- 嗨，呱镇。
- Uh, what is this?
- 呃，这是什么？
all: Quadtown!
所有人: 四镇！
- We're jamming here too. - All right, guys,
- 我们也在即兴演奏。 - 好吧，伙计们，
how loud are we gonna get?
我们打算多大声？
Ear-bleeding or brain-melting?
震耳欲聋还是脑浆沸腾？
- Let's melt some brains!
让我们沸腾一些脑浆！
- Two, three, four! - ♪ Squishy! Squishy! ♪
二，三，四！
♪ He's our pet ♪
他是我们的宠物
♪ He's so cute you won't forget ♪
他太可爱了，你忘不掉
♪ You haven't heard the best part yet ♪
你还没听到最精彩的部分
♪ Touch his nose ♪
摸摸他的鼻子
♪ It's a little wet! ♪
有点湿漉漉的！
[barks]
汪汪
- They think they can out-rock us?
他们以为能比我们更摇滚？
[scoffs]
哼
[rock music] - ♪ Ribbit! Ribbit! ♪
♪ 呱！呱！ ♪
- It's time to bring out our...
是时候拿出我们的...
secret weapon!
秘密武器了！
- Did someone call for The Tomahawk?
有人呼叫战斧吗？
[caws]
嘎
Hit it, Quadtown!
来吧，Quadtown！
[disorganized music]
♪ ♪
- You know, if we're too loud for you,
你知道，如果我们太吵了，
you can go home!
你可以回家！
- Never! Come on, Frogtown!
绝不！来吧，Frogtown！
[rock music]
- ♪ Ribbit! Ribbit! ♪
♪ 呱！呱！ ♪
♪ ♪
- All right, let's give it to 'em!
好吧，让我们给他们看看！
- ♪ Ribbit! Ribbit! ♪
♪ 呱！呱！ ♪
[all playing at once]
♪ ♪
[howls]
[嚎叫]
- ♪ Ribbit! Ribbit! ♪
- ♪ 呱！呱！ ♪
[all continue to play at once]
[所有人继续同时演奏]
- What? You too scared to keep playing?
- 什么？你也害怕继续玩吗？
Quadtown rules...
四街规则...
Are very important to every household.
对每个家庭都非常重要。
- Oh, hey, Mom, you're home early.
- 哦，嘿，妈妈，你提前回来了。
- Yeah, I couldn't relax at the spa.
- 是的，我在水疗中心无法放松。
I think it's time you boys went home now.
我想现在你们男孩们该回家了。
- But we signed a rental agreement.
- 但我们签了租赁协议。
- Declan McManus, would you like me to call your mother?
- Declan McManus，需要我给你妈妈打电话吗？
- No, ma'am. We're out.
- 不用了，女士。我们这就走。
- Okay, let's go. Let's go. Thank you.
- 好的，我们走吧。谢谢。
- [hisses] - I heard that, Jeffrey.
- [嘶声] - 我听到了，Jeffrey。
- Sss... sorry, Mrs. Harper.
- 嘘... 对不起，Harper太太。
- [sighs]
- [叹气]
- Okay, this is not what it looks like.
- 好吧，这不是看起来那样。
- See, the thing is--
- 事情是这样的——
[all speaking at once]
[所有人同时说话]
- Kids, kids, quiet. Quiet.
- 孩子们，安静。安静。
[whispers] Mom's smiling.
妈妈在微笑。
What are you smiling at?
你在笑什么？
- The kids. You.
孩子们。你。
This is my happy place.
这里是我的快乐之地。
all: It is? - It is.
真的吗？ - 真的。
- You-- you're not mad?
你——你不生气吗？
- To be honest I expected a lot worse.
老实说，我以为情况会更糟。
I mean, everyone's wearing pants.
我是说，大家都有穿裤子。
The couch isn't on fire, and there's no donkeys.
沙发没有着火，也没有驴子。
I'm good.
我很好。
- Yes. Super Dad does it again.
- Mom, Dad, we're really sorry. - Yeah.
None of this would have happened if we'd just followed the rules.
- Guess that's why you guys make them for us.
- Well, I guess there's only one thing left for you to do.
- Clean up? - Yep.
But first, why don't you play me that song?
- This one's for a very special lady named Mom.
- Two, three, four! - all: ♪ Squishy! Squishy! ♪
♪ He's our pet ♪
♪ And he's so cute you won't forget ♪
♪ 而且他非常可爱 ♪ ♪ 你永远不会忘记 ♪
- Wow. They are loud.
- 哇。他们声音真大。
- It's music to my ears. - all: ♪ It's a little wet! ♪ [disorganized music]
- 对我来说这是美妙的音乐。 ♪ 有点湿！ ♪
[whistling]
♪ ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ 耶，耶，耶， ♪ ♪ 耶，耶 ♪
♪ 耶，耶， ♪ ♪ 耶，耶，耶 ♪
- ♪ Yeah! ♪
- ♪ 耶！ ♪
- ♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
- ♪ 耶，耶，耶， ♪ ♪ 耶，耶 ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ 耶，耶，耶，耶 ♪
- ♪ Yeah! ♪
- ♪ 耶！ ♪